<resources>
    <string name="app_name">EnglishNewspaper</string>

    <string-array name="news_titles">
        <item>Deterioration of law and order increases concern over peaceful democratic transition: SAHR</item>
        <item>Hasina ‘forced false testimony’ against Sayedee: Witnesses</item>
        <item>Editors’ Council expresses concerns over three issues</item>
        <item>Gang-rape threat to DUCSU candidate: DU expels student for 6 months</item>
        <item>Approver’s testimony July mass killings ordered by Hasina, Asaduzzaman Khan</item>
        <item>Chief Adviser orders to send Nur abroad for treatment</item>
        <item>Deterioration of law and order increases concern over peaceful democratic transition: SAHR</item>
        <item>Is BNP prepared for a new Bangladesh?</item>
        <item>So, will Aminul contest against Tamim for the position of BCB President?</item>
        <item>Reforms: When will the police be an institution for the people?</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Subtitles -->
    <string-array name="news_subtitles">
        <item>India now allows Bangladesh’s religious minorities to stay without documentation.</item>
        <item>EC has proposed barring individuals declared fugitives by courts from parliamentary polls.</item>
        <item>The Editors’ Council raised alarm over mob entering DRU and AI-generated image dispute.</item>
        <item>Inspector General of Police says 4,000 ASIs will be recruited ahead of national election.</item>
        <item>DUCSU VP candidate Sk Tasnim Afroz says female candidates face bullying and online harassment.</item>
        <item>Chief Adviser Professor Yunus orders arrangements to send Nur abroad for advanced treatment following serious injuries.</item>
        <item>SAHR voices anxiety over worsening law and order and its implications for democratic transition.</item>
        <item>Opinion piece examines whether BNP is ready for a new chapter in Bangladesh’s politics.</item>
        <item>Aminul Islam Shamsul Hoque hints he might contest again for BCB President if nominated.</item>
        <item>Editor Rashed Al Mahmud Titumir reflects on police’s colonial roots and current militarisation.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Times -->
    <string-array name="news_times">
        <item>26 minutes ago</item>
        <item>15:50</item>
        <item>16:50</item>
        <item>13:05</item>
        <item>15:25</item>
        <item>04:05</item>
        <item>16:28</item>
        <item>01 Sep 2025, 13:51</item>
        <item>02 Sep 2025, 12:31</item>
        <item>02 Sep 2025, 02:34</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="news_fullstories">
    <item>India now allows Bangladesh’s religious minorities to stay without documentation.
    The move is seen as part of a broader policy shift to provide humanitarian support.
    Many rights organisations have welcomed the decision, though concerns remain about
    long-term integration and social impact.</item>

        <item>The Election Commission has proposed barring individuals declared fugitives by courts
    from parliamentary polls. The move sparked debate among political analysts, with some
    saying it strengthens accountability, while others argue it could be misused politically.</item>

        <item>The Editors’ Council raised alarm over incidents where mobs entered the DRU office,
    and controversy erupted over AI-generated images being used in political campaigns.
    Journalists demanded greater protection and transparency ahead of the election.</item>

        <item>Inspector General of Police announced recruitment of 4,000 assistant sub-inspectors
    (ASIs) ahead of the upcoming national election. Officials claim this will help strengthen
    security, though opposition leaders worry it might be used for political purposes.</item>

        <item>DUCSU VP candidate Sk Tasnim Afroz highlighted the challenges faced by women in
    politics, including bullying and online harassment. She urged the Election Commission
    and universities to take stronger measures to ensure safety for female candidates.</item>

        <item>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus instructed authorities to make urgent
    arrangements to send Nur abroad for advanced treatment after he suffered severe injuries.
    The case has drawn national attention, with widespread calls for justice.</item>

        <item>South Asians for Human Rights (SAHR) voiced concern over the deteriorating law
    and order situation in Bangladesh, warning that it could jeopardize peaceful democratic
    transition. They called for urgent government action to ensure safety of communities.</item>

        <item>An opinion column analyzed whether the BNP is prepared for a new chapter in
    Bangladesh’s politics, highlighting internal divisions, leadership challenges, and the
    growing demand from grassroots members for reforms before the election.</item>

        <item>Aminul Islam Shamsul Hoque hinted at running again for BCB President if nominated.
    Cricket insiders suggest that his decision may reshape the board’s leadership dynamics
    and potentially influence Bangladesh’s cricketing strategy.</item>

        <item>Editor Rashed Al Mahmud Titumir discussed how the police’s colonial roots
    continue to shape its militarised structure today, calling for urgent reforms to
    improve accountability, transparency, and trust between citizens and law enforcement.</item>
    </string-array>


</resources>